<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="ipcentry-double.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<ipcEntries displayMode="e19800101;a19800101;c19800101" ipcLevel="c" split="subclass" languages=",en,fr," size="48794">
	<ipcEntry kind="s" symbol="C" ipcLevel="C" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
		<textBody><title>
				<titlePart><text>SECTION C <emdash></emdash> CHEMISTRY AND METALLURGY</text>
				</titlePart>
			</title>
		</textBody>
		<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
			<textBody>
				<note type="none">
					<noteParagraph><text>Definitions for Section C: </text>
						<subnote type="bullet">
							<noteParagraph><text>Alkali metals: Li, Na, K, Rb, Cs, Fr </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Alkaline earth metals: Ca, Sr, Ba, Ra </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Lanthanides: elements with atomic numbers 57 to 71 inclusive </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Rare earths: Sc, Y, Lanthanides </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Actinides: elements with atomic numbers 89 to 103 inclusive </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Refractory metals: Ti, V, Cr, Zr, Nb, Mo, Hf, Ta, W </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Halogens: F, Cl, Br, I, At </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Noble gases: He, Ne, Ar, Kr, Xe, Rn </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Platinum group: Os, Ir, Pt, Ru, Rh, Pd </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Noble metals: Ag, Au, Platinum group </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Light metals: alkali metals, alkaline earth metals, Be, Al, Mg </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Heavy metals: metals other than light metals </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Iron group: Fe, Co, Ni </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Non-metals: H, B, C, Si, N, P, O, S, Se, Te, noble gases, halogens </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Metals: elements other than non-metals </text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>Transition elements: elements with atomic numbers 21 to 30 inclusive, 39 to 48 inclusive, 57 to 80 inclusive, 89 upwards</text>
							</noteParagraph>
						</subnote>
					</noteParagraph>
				</note>
			</textBody>
		</ipcEntry>
		<ipcEntry kind="t" symbol="C01" endSymbol="C01" ipcLevel="C" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
			<textBody><title>
					<titlePart><text>CHEMISTRY</text>
					</titlePart>
				</title>
			</textBody>
		</ipcEntry>
		<ipcEntry kind="c" symbol="C07" ipcLevel="C" edition="19740701" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
			<textBody><title>
					<titlePart><text>ORGANIC CHEMISTRY</text>
						<entryReference>such compounds as the oxides, sulphides, and oxysulphides of carbon, cyanogen, phosgene, hydrocyanic acid and salts thereof <sref ref="C01" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
						</entryReference>
						<entryReference>macromolecular compounds <sref ref="C08" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
						</entryReference>
						<entryReference>dyes <sref ref="C09" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
						</entryReference>
						<entryReference>fermentation products <sref ref="C12" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
						</entryReference>
						<entryReference>fermentation or enzyme-using processes to synthesise a desired chemical compound <sref ref="C12P" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
						</entryReference>
						<entryReference>production of organic compounds by electrolysis or electrophoresis <sref ref="C25B0003000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
						</entryReference>
					</titlePart>
				</title>
			</textBody>
			<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C07" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody>
					<note type="number">
						<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>Anhydrides and halides of carboxylic acids are classified as the relevant acids unless otherwise indicated. Salts of a compound, unless specifically provided for, are classified as that compound, e.g. aniline hydrochloride is classified as containing carbon, hydrogen and nitrogen only (in <sref ref="C07C0087520000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>), sodium malonate is classified as malonic acid (in <sref ref="C07C0055080000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>), and a mercaptide is classified as the mercaptan. Metal chelates are dealt with in the same way. Similarly, metal alcoholates and metal phenates are classified in sub-class <sref ref="C07C" refType="/" refLevel="c"/> and not in sub-class <sref ref="C07F" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>
								<emdash/> the alcoholates in <mref ref="C07C0031280000" endRef="C07C0031320000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/> and the phenates as the corresponding phenols in <sref ref="C07C0039235000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/> or <sref ref="C07C0039440000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>. Salts or adducts formed between two or more organic compounds are classified according to all compounds forming the salts or adducts.</text>
						</noteParagraph>
						<noteParagraph><text>In the absence of an indication to the contrary, and with the exception referred to below, a compound is classified in the last appropriate place, e.g. a compound containing an acyclic chain and a heterocyclic ring is classified only as a heterocyclic compound, and a steroid is classified only as a cyclopentanophenanthrene compound. In general, and in the absence of an indication to the contrary (such as groups <sref ref="C07C0059580000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>, <sref ref="C07C0059700000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>), the terms "acyclic" and "aliphatic" are used to describe compounds in which there is no ring; and, if a ring were present, the compound would be taken by the "last place" rule to a later group for cycloaliphatic or aromatic compounds, if such a group exists. Where a compound or an entire group of compounds exists in tautomeric forms, it is classified as though existing in the form which is classified last in the system, unless the other form is specifically mentioned earlier in the system.</text>
						</noteParagraph>
						<noteParagraph><text>Albumens, proteins, alkaloids of unknown structure, glucosides of unknown structure are examples of compounds to be found unter <sref ref="C07G" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>.</text>
						</noteParagraph>
						<noteParagraph><text>Inventions dealing with chemical compounds and their preparation are classified in the groups for the type of compound prepared. The processes of preparation should be secondarily classified in the groups for the types of reaction employed when such groups exist. General processes for the preparation of a class of compounds falling into more than one main group are classified in the groups for the processes employed when such groups exist. The compounds prepared may be secondarily classified in the groups for the types of compounds prepared.</text>
						</noteParagraph>
					</note>
				</textBody>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07B" ipcLevel="C" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>GENERAL METHODS AND APPARATUS OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY</text>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07C" ipcLevel="C" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>ACYCLIC AND CARBOCYCLIC COMPOUNDS</text>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
				<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C07C" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
					<textBody>
						<note type="number">
							<noteParagraph><text>Inventions dealing with chemical compounds and their preparation are classified in the groups for the type of compound prepared. The processes of preparation should be secondarily classified in the groups for the types of reactions employed when such groups exist. General processes for the preparation of a class of compounds falling into more than one main group are classified in the groups for the processes employed when such groups exist. The compounds prepared may be secondarily classified in the groups for the types of compounds prepared.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>The term "preparation" in main-groups is to be understood as including purification, separation or stabilisation unless a separate main-group is provided therefor.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph edition="19800101"><text>In the absence of an indication to the contrary, a process is always classified in the last appropriate place in this sub-class.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
						</note>
					</textBody>
				</ipcEntry>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07D" ipcLevel="C" edition="19740701" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>HETEROCYCLIC COMPOUNDS</text>
							<entryReference>cyclo-peptides, peptides containing proline, hydroxyproline, histidine or tryptophane <sref ref="C07C0103520000" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>steroids containing hetero rings <sref ref="C07J" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
				<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C07D" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
					<textBody>
						<note type="number">
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>A compound containing a saccharide radical is classified in <sref ref="C07H" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>. For a definition of the therm "saccharide radical", see <sref ref="C07H" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>Where a compound may exist in tautomeric forms, it is classified as though existing in the form which is classified last in the system. Therefore, double bonds between ring members and non-ring members and double bonds between ring members themselves are considered equivalent in determining the degree of hydrogenation of the ring. Formulae are considered to be written in Kekule form.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>For the purpose of this sub-class, the following definitions apply:</text>
								<subnote type="alpha">
									<noteParagraph><text>A "hetero ring" is a ring having at least one halogen, nitrogen, oxygen, sulphur, selenium, or tellurium atom as a ring member.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>Two rings are "condensed" if they share at least one ring member, i.e. "spiro" and "bridged" are considered as condensed. The term "bridged" denotes the presence of at least one fusion other than ortho, peri, and spiro.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>A "condensed ring system" is a ring system in which all rings are condensed among themselves.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>The "number of relevant rings" in a condensed ring system equals the number of scissions necessary to convert the ring system into one acyclic chain.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>The "relevant rings" in a condensed ring system, i.e. the rings which taken together describe all the links between every atom of the ring system, are chosen according to the following criteria consecutively:</text>
										<subnote type="roman">
											<noteParagraph><text>Lowest number of ring members;</text>
											</noteParagraph>
											<noteParagraph><text>Highest number of hetero atoms as ring members;</text>
											</noteParagraph>
											<noteParagraph><text>Lowest number of members shared with other rings;</text>
											</noteParagraph>
											<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>Last place in the classification scheme.</text>
											</noteParagraph>
										</subnote>
									</noteParagraph>
								</subnote>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph><text>For the purpose of classification, the following rules apply:</text>
								<subnote type="alpha">
									<noteParagraph><text>Compounds having only one hetero ring are classified in the last appropriate place in one of the groups <mref ref="C07D0203000000" endRef="C07D0347000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/>. The same applies for compounds having more hetero rings covered by the same main group, neither condensed among themselves nor condensed with a common carbocyclic ring system.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>Compounds having two or more hetero rings covered by different main groups neither condensed among themselves nor condensed with a common carbocyclic ring system are classified in the last appropriate place in one of the groups <mref ref="C07D0401000000" endRef="C07D0421000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/>.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>Compounds having two or more relevant hetero rings, covered by the same or by different main groups, which are condensed among themselves or condensed with a common carbocyclic ring system, are classified in the last appropriate place in one of the groups <mref ref="C07D0451000000" endRef="C07D0519000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/>.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>Hydrocarbon radicals containing a carbocyclic ring and an acyclic chain by which it is linked to the hetero ring and being substituted on both the carbocyclic ring and the acyclic chain by hetero atoms or by carbon atoms having three bonds to hetero atoms with at the most one bond to halogen, are classified according to the substituents on the acyclic chain. For example, the compound <img src="fig54.gif"/> is classified in group <sref ref="C07D0233220000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>, and the compound <img src="fig55.gif"/> is classified in groups <sref ref="C07D0233240000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/> and <sref ref="C07D0233260000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>, where X <emdash/>NH<sub>2</sub>, <emdash/>NHCOCH<sub>3</sub>, or <emdash/>COOCH<sub>3</sub>.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph edition="19800101"><text>In compounds containing a hetero ring covered by group <sref ref="C07D0295000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/> and at least one other hetero ring, the hetero ring covered by group <sref ref="C07D0295000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/> is considered as an acyclic chain containing nitrogen atoms.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
								</subnote>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph edition="19800101"><text>In this sub-class it is desirable to add, in conformity with paragraph 80 of the Guide, after the double oblique stroke the symbols relating to complementary information concerning individual constituents of a technical subject which is already classified as such. The set of classification symbols allotted to such complementary information is placed between brackets; first, the classification symbol of the technical subject is indicated again, followed by the symbol relating to each of the individual components, chosen according to the following guidelines:</text>
								<subnote type="alpha">
									<noteParagraph edition="19800101"><text>For compounds classified in groups <mref ref="C07D0203000000" endRef="C07D0347000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/> one or more appropriate places which precede the classification place may be given as complementary information, e.g. in order to show essential substituents.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph edition="19800101"><text>In compounds containing two or more hetero rings covered by different main groups, neither condensed among themselves nor with a common carbocyclic ring system, each hetero ring is shown as complementary information. The appropriate marks are determined by scission of all other hetero rings and considering them as substituents. The locations of the scissions are chosen so as to obtain the substituents which appear in the later place in the classification, e.g. the relevant rings of <img src="fig56.gif"/> are considered to be <img src="fig57.gif"/></text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph><text>For compounds containing one condensed ring system having two or more relevant hetero rings, and for which no specific group is provided, all relevant rings having hetero atoms as ring members are shown as complementary information. These rings are indicated by the main group symbols of groups <mref ref="C07D0203000000" endRef="C07D0347000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/>, except of groups <sref ref="C07D0207000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>, <mref ref="C07D0211000000" endRef="C07D0219000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/>, <sref ref="C07D0233000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>, <sref ref="C07D0295000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/> and <sref ref="C07D0309000000" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>For compounds containing two ore more condensed ring systems each having two or more hetero rings, each condensed system is shown as complementary information. The appropriate marks are found in the groups <mref ref="C07D0451000000" endRef="C07D0517000000" refType="/" endRefType="/" refLevel="c" endRefLevel="c"/> and determined by considering separately each condensed system in turn.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
								</subnote>
							</noteParagraph>
						</note>
					</textBody>
				</ipcEntry>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07F" ipcLevel="C" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>ACYCLIC, CARBOCYCLIC, OR HETEROCYCLIC COMPOUNDS CONTAINING ELEMENTS OTHER THAN CARBON, HYDROGEN, HALOGEN, OXYGEN, NITROGEN, SULPHUR, SELENIUM, OR TELLURIUM</text>
							<entryReference>metal-containing porphyrins <sref ref="C07D0487220000" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
				<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C07F" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
					<textBody>
						<note type="none">
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>Organic acid salts, alcoholates, phenates, chelates or mercaptides are classified as the parent compounds. Attention is also drawn to Note (1) following the class title of class <sref ref="C07" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
						</note>
					</textBody>
				</ipcEntry>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07G" ipcLevel="C" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>COMPOUNDS OF UNKNOWN CONSTITUTION</text>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07H" ipcLevel="C" edition="19740701" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>SUGARS</text>
						</titlePart>
						<titlePart><text>DERIVATIVES THEREOF</text>
							<entryReference>derivatives of aldonic or saccharic acids <sref ref="C07C" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>, <sref ref="C07D" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>aldonic acids, saccharic acids <sref ref="C07C0059105000" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>, <sref ref="C07C0059285000" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>cyanohydrins <sref ref="C07C0121360000" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>glycals <sref ref="C07D" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>compounds of unknown constitution <sref ref="C07G" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>polysaccharides, derivatives thereof <sref ref="C08B" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
							<entryReference>sugar and starch industry <sref ref="C13" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
				<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C07H" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
					<textBody>
						<note type="number">
							<noteParagraph><text>This sub-class is concerned with compounds containing saccharide radicals. Excluded are polysaccharides which for the purpose of this sub-class are defined as having more than five saccharide radicals attached to each other by glycosidic linkages. A "saccharide radical" is derived from acyclic polyhydroxy-aldehydes or acyclic polyhydroxy-ketones, or from their cyclic tautomers, by removing hydrogen atoms or by replacing hetero bonds to oxygen by the same number of hetero bonds to halogen, nitrogen, sulphur, selenium, or tellurium, in accordance with either of the following definitions:</text>
								<subnote type="alpha">
									<noteParagraph><text>A "saccharide radical"</text>
										<subnote type="roman">
											<noteParagraph><text>consists of an uninterrupted carbon skeleton and oxygen atoms directly attached thereto, and</text>
											</noteParagraph>
											<noteParagraph><text>is considered to be terminated by every bond to a cyclic structure and by every bond to a carbon atom having three bonds to hetero atoms, e.g. ester or nitrile radicals, and</text>
											</noteParagraph>
											<noteParagraph><text>contains within the carbon skeleton an unconjugated sequence of at the most six carbon atoms in which at least three carbon atoms <emdash/> at least two in the case of a skeleton having only four carbon atoms <emdash/> have one single bond to an oxygen atom as the only hetero bond, and</text>
												<subnote type="Alpha">
													<noteParagraph><text>in a cyclic or acyclic sequence, at least one other carbon atom has two single bonds to oxygen atoms as the only hetero bonds, or</text>
													</noteParagraph>
													<noteParagraph><text>in an acyclic sequence, at least one other carbon atom has one double bond to an oxygen atom as the only hetero bond.</text>
													</noteParagraph>
												</subnote>
											</noteParagraph>
										</subnote>
									</noteParagraph>
									<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>A "saccharide radical" is also a radical derived from a radical as defined in (a) above by replacing at the most four of the specified hetero bonds to oxygen by the same number of hetero bonds to halogen, nitrogen, sulphur, selenium, or tellurium.</text>
									</noteParagraph>
								</subnote>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>Attention is drawn to the notes following the title of class <sref ref="C07" refType="/" refLevel="c"/>.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>In the absence of an indication to the contrary, a compound is classified in the last appropriate place.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>The terms "heterocyclic radical" and "hetero ring" are considered to exclude saccharide radicals as defined above.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
						</note>
					</textBody>
				</ipcEntry>
			</ipcEntry>
			<ipcEntry kind="u" symbol="C07J" ipcLevel="C" edition="19740701" entryType="K" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
				<textBody><title>
						<titlePart><text>STEROIDS</text>
							<entryReference>seco-steroids <sref ref="C07C" refType="/" refLevel="c"></sref>
							</entryReference>
						</titlePart>
					</title>
				</textBody>
				<ipcEntry kind="n" symbol="C07J" entryType="K" ipcLevel="C" isRenumbered="N" isDead="N" lang="EN" noadvanced="yes">
					<textBody>
						<note type="none">
							<noteParagraph edition="19740701"><text>This sub-class comprises compounds containing a cyclopenta (a) phenanthrene skeleton or a ring structure derived therefrom by contraction or expansion of one ring by one or two atoms, by contraction or expansion of two rings each by one atom, by contraction of one ring by one atom and expansion of one ring by one atom, by substitution of one or two carbon atoms of the cyclopenta (a) phenanthrene skeleton by hetero atoms, in combination with the above defined contraction or expansion or not, or by condensation with carbocyclic or heterocyclic rings in combination with one or more of the foregoing alterations or not.</text>
							</noteParagraph>
						</note>
					</textBody>
				</ipcEntry>
			</ipcEntry>
		</ipcEntry>
	</ipcEntry>
</ipcEntries>
